Gerriss Gailey

Full-stack web developer versed in both front and back end web development, yet always learning. Experienced CAD Designer in mechanical design and development of machine components. Experienced with Visual Studio Code, Solidworks, Fusion 360, and Microsoft Office.

St. George, UT (801) 979-4251

gerrissgailey@gmail.com LinkedIn: Gerriss Gailey GitHub: Gerriss Gailey

EXPERIENCE

Cathtip, St. George, UT —CAD Draftsman / Mechanical Designer

JANUARY 2016 - PRESENT

- CAD design of mechanical tooling assemblies for customer catheter development projects to be used on Cathtip Magnum and Quantum tipping machines.
- Generate technical drawings of tooling components to meet customer catheter design specs.
- CAD database management & revision control.
- Development of catheter tipping machine components.
- Oversee design of a semi-automated catheter cutting machine.
- Rapid prototyping and development with 3D printing.

Calvary Chapel, St. George, UT — Assistant Pastor

MARCH 2013 - MARCH 2016

- Oversee and direct children's ministry services & activities for a ministry of 120+ children.
- Preaching, teaching, instruction of children's ministry and young adult ministry.
- Curriculum development for Sunday School & midweek bible studies.
- Managed a team of roughly 60 children's ministry volunteers, designed training/development curriculum and materials, to equip volunteers to teach in a Sunday School & midweek bible study environment.
- Conference, mission trip, and summer camp planning and oversight.

Ram Company, St. George, UT — CNC Machinist Apprentice

FEBRUARY 2012 - MARCH 2013

- Operate Mazak 3 and 4 axis CNC machines
- Operate Swiss Lathe CNC machine
- Operate manual mills, surface grinders, lathes.
- Precision machining & measurement of parts to meet technical drawing specifications.

SKILLS

Proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Proficient in engineering & design software including Solidworks, Fusion 360, & various 3D Printing slicers.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Catheter Cutting Machine
Oversight & design of a
custom semi-automated
cutting machine for a
customer specific catheter
manufacturing application.

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES & TECHNOLOGIES

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, NodeJS, Express, MySQL, Sequelize, React

EDUCATION

University of Utah Coding Bootcamp, Certificate of Completion

NOVEMBER 2020 - MAY 2021

Six month full-stack web development coding bootcamp. Rigorous curriculum covering a full-stack: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, MongoDB, MySQL, Git, etc.

PROJECTS

Middle-Earth Supplier Web App

This was a team project which we had a lot of fun with. A Lord of the Rings themed shopping app with a customer focused front end to shop for various "Middle-Earth" sourced items, and an employee focused login area to process orders submitted. Languages include HTML, CSS, JavaSCript. Technologies & packages include MySQL, Handlebars, Express, Passport, Sequelize.

This web app can be viewed by <u>clicking here</u>.

Decider Diner Web App

This was a team project, the goal of which was to design a real-world web application that utilizes at least two third party APIs to call data from. In this case, our app was designed to be a resource that would return suggestions for either cooking at home or eating out based on user input. Languages used include: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery.

This web app can be viewed by clicking here.

Weather Dashboard Web App

Designed to be a quick resource to enter city or zip code and have the current day weather and a 5-day forecast returned. Will also store recent location search history. Languages used include: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery.

This web app can be viewed by clicking here.

Work Day Scheduler Web App

Designed to be a simple daytime planner/scheduler web application that highlights the current time & task, as well as past and upcoming hours of the day. Languages used include: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ¡Query.

This web app can be viewed by clicking here.